Inventory of the Institute for Soviet American Relations records
Hoover Institution Archives
Institute for Soviet American Relations records
1986-2003
2007C68
Hoover Institution Archives
10 manuscript boxes (4.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, proposals, financial records, serial issues, and other printed matter relating to Soviet-American cultural relations, relations between the United States and the successor states to the Soviet Union, and environmental programs in those states.
Institute for Soviet American Relations (U.S.)
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The Institute for Soviet American Relations, established in 1983, is a private American nonprofit organization for the promotion of cultural relations between the United States and the Soviet Union.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, proposals, financial records, serial issues, and other printed matter relating to Soviet-American cultural relations, relations between the United States and the successor states to the Soviet Union, and environmental programs in those states.
Environmental policy--Former Soviet republics.; Former Soviet republics--Relations--United States.; Soviet Union--Relations--United States.; United States--Relations--Former Soviet republics.; United States--Relations--Soviet Union.
- Anatoly Lebedev corrrespondence, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Ecoforum Conference correspondence, 1995 May (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Ecoforum press, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Ecoforum originals, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Ecoforum directory, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- West Newly Independent States of the Former Soviet Union (NIS) Board, meetings and agendas, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- West NIS Board, members and policies, 1995 - 1998 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Conference mailings, 1991 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Agency for International Development (AID) Grant Program: Ukraine, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Institute for Soviet American Relations (ISAR) Socio-Ecological Union (SEU) Membership Dialogue, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- SEU/AID Project, early seeds and documents, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- ISAR, Ann Rubin project, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 12)
- Al Gore visit to Russian NGOs, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 13)
- ISAR, new Board packets, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 14)
- ISAR, Almaty email, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 1: 15)
- Conference publicity, 1991 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Radio Free Europe (RFE) admin, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- ISAR/SEU affiliation, undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
- AID/RFE, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- DevTech terms and conditions, proposals, contracts, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- RFE Press, Far East, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Ecocenter, Far East, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Regional Investment Initiative for RFE and US-Russian Environmental Non-Governmental Organizations (NGOs), 1998 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Kazakhstan, Apostille documents, 2002 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- ISAR proceedings, 1999 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- University of Maryland International Instance of Environmental Policy, 1997 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- Initiative for Ecological Learning in Russian schools, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- Ukraine, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- ISAR Azerbaijan, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- NGOs and the future, 1997 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Azerbaijan program, small grants, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Nukus trip reports, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Central Asia trip reports, 1996 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Bill Newton's trip reports, 1996 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Quarterly reports, Almaty, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Central Asia monthly reports, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- Trip reports, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- ISAR, Cholpon Ata Board business, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- Central Asia Board of Management documents, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 12)
- ISAR Central Asia photos, 1994 (Box-folder 3: 13)
- Central Asia Board of Directors meetings, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3: 14)
- ISAR and SEU emails, 1992 March-May (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Oleg Cherp, Ecologia, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- World Learning, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Arrangements for Maria Cherkasova's 1990 trip (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Maria Cherkosova articles, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- Gulaisha Esemuratova, 1992 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- Londa Khasaia and Jekshenbeck Jamgyrchiev, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Mati Rahu, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Ludmilla Zhirina, 1994 (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Oral Atanyazova, Uzebekistan trip, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Maria Cherkasova correspondence, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Surviving Together: A Journal on Soviet-American Relations, 1986 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- Surviving Together: A Journal on Soviet-American Relations, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 13)
- Surviving Together: A Journal on Soviet-American Relations, 1988 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- Surviving Together: A Journal on Soviet-American Relations, 1989 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- Surviving Together: A Journal on Soviet-American Relations, 1990 (Box-folder 5: 3)
- Surviving Together: A Journal on Soviet-American Relations, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- Surviving Together: A Journal on Relations with the Former Soviet Union, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- Surviving Together: A Quarterly on Grassroots Cooperation in Eurasia, 1994 (Box-folder 5: 7)
- Surviving Together: A Quarterly on Grassroots Cooperation in Eurasia, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Surviving Together: A Quarterly on Grassroots Cooperation in Eurasia, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 2)
- Surviving Together: A Quarterly on Grassroots Cooperation in Eurasia, 1997 (Box-folder 6: 3)
- Give & Take: A Journal on Civil Society in Eurasia, 1998 (Box-folder 6: 4)
- Give & Take: A Journal on Civil Society in Eurasia, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 6: 5)
- Give & Take: A Journal on Civil Society in Eurasia, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 6)
- Give & Take: A Journal on Civil Society in Eurasia, 2001 (Box-folder 6: 7)
- Give & Take: A Journal on Civil Society in Eurasia, 2002 (Box-folder 6: 8)
- Give & Take: A Journal on Civil Society in Eurasia, 2003 (Box-folder 6: 9)
- Mike Clayton's trip reports, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Georgia program materials, 1996 (Box-folder 7: 2)
- ISAR Georgia newsletters, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- Frank Montero, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7: 4)
- Caucasus Board materials and management, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 5)
- Georgia, David Gareja, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes photographs of monasteries in the David Gareja area.
- ISAR Georgia grants, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 7: 7)
- ISAR-Georgia, Phase One, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 7: 8)
- ISAR-Georgia, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7: 9)
- ISAR-Georgia success stories, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 10)
- ISAR-Georgia training, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7: 11)
- Georgia, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7: 12)
- ISAR-Georgia, Mike Clayton recommendation and essays, 1998 (Box-folder 7: 13)
- Central Asia trip reports, 1996 (Box-folder 7: 14)
- World Bank and NGOs, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 7: 15)
- Climate Change Aid, 1998 (Box-folder 7: 16)
- Kazakhstan Green Salvation, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Kazakhstan Casdin, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 2)
- NGO/donor report distribution, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Anvar Buzurukov, Tajikistan, 1979-1994 (Box-folder 8: 4)
- Seeds Program, Ideas for the Future, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 8: 5)
- Sila Dvizheniya (book), 1998 (Box-folder 8: 6)
- Horizonti-ISAR subgrantee agreement, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Horizonti/ISAR, 1999 (Box-folder 8: 8)
- Memorandum of agreement and subgrant agreement, 1998 (Box-folder 8: 9)
- Horizonti partnership documents, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8: 10)
- Horizonti audit (report and financial statements), 1998 (Box-folder 8: 11)
- ISAR-Horizonti memorandom of understanding, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 8: 12)
- Sultonbekov vs. ISAR, 1996 (Box-folder 8: 13)
- Horizonti audit (report and financial statements), 1999 (Box-folder 8: 14)
- Horizonti Governing Board and information, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 15)
- Georgian NGOs directory, 1998 (Box-folder 8: 16)
- Environmental NGOs in the Caucasus, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 17)
- West Sector funding and Board meetings, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 8: 18)
- ISAR-Georgia email, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 8: 19)
- Anvar Buzurukov, Tajikistan, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 9: 1)
- Ecolog, Oleg Tsanuk, 1994 (Box-folder 9: 2)
- Address from NGOs, 1996 (Box-folder 9: 3)
- NGO/donor working group, 1997 (Box-folder 9: 4)
- Central Asia representative, 1997 (Box-folder 9: 5)
- Azerbaijan early management issues, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 9: 6)
- NGO/donor workshop, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 9: 7)
- NGOs in Kazakhstan, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 9: 8)
- Azerbaijan PR documents, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 9: 9)
- Registering in Azerbaijan, 1996 (Box-folder 9: 10)
- Azerbaijan/Georgia amendment, 1997 (Box-folder 9: 11)
- Azerbaijan NGO assessment, 1999 (Box-folder 9: 12)
- Azerbaijan financial documents, 2001 (Box-folder 9: 13)
- NGOs in Kyrgyzstan, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 9: 14)
- Environment funding roundtable, 1992 (Box-folder 10: 1)
- Volunteer program information/application forms, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 10: 2)
- World Bank Oil and Gas Contract, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 10: 3)
- NGO Coalition for the NIS, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 10: 4)
- NGOs in Tajikistan, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 10: 5)
- NGOs in Turkmenistan, 1996 (Box-folder 10: 6)
- Turkmenistan Catena: Ashgabat Ecology Club, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 10: 7)
- Karakalpakstan, Union for the Defense of the Aral Sea and Amu Darya, 1992, 1997 (Box-folder 10: 8)
- Karakalpakstan Perzent, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 10: 9)
- Uzbekistan Women's Resource Center, 1996 (Box-folder 10: 10)
- NGOs in Uzbekistan, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 10: 11)
- AID-2 Grant Making Project proposal documents, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 10: 12)